ndrea **Geme**

📳 +39 3319952716 | 🔀 gemelli.andrea@hotmail.com | 💣 https://andreagemelli.github.io | 🖸 github.com/andreagemelli | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/andrea-gemelli/

Profile Summary_

A Computer Science professional with 3+ years of experience, holding a MSc degree and actively pursuing a PhD in Machine Learning. Strong background in Graph Neural Networks, Document Analysis, and Natural Language Processing, highly interested and research-oriented towards language and vision and the latest trends on Large Language Models.

Work Experience _

AI Lab - University of Florence

Florence, Italy

Ph.D. Student Nov 2020 - ongoing

- Focused on the application of Graph Neural Networks to Document Understanding and Natural Language Processing related tasks.
- Worked as a visiting researcher at **Computer Vision Center** for a year.
- · Attended several international conferences and summer schools: the International Computer Vision Summer School (ICVSS), selected among 600+ applicants with 30% acceptance rate - the Cambridge ELLIS Machine Learning Summer School, selected among 260+ applicants with 50% acceptance rate - and the **4th IAPR Summer School on Document Analysis**, winning the 2^{nd} price at the organized hackathon.
- · Taught two university courses as a tutor, held several lectures, followed bachelor and master students in their projects and thesis.

Alias2k Montevarchi, Italy

Data Scientist

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018

- Developed machine learning based solutions to improve the effectiveness of company's softwares.
- Final work personally presented to the CEO of Avesco Rent in Lausanne.

Education

University of Florence Florence, Italy

MSc in Computer Science and Engineering

2017 - 2020

- Graduated with full marks (110/110). Thesis: "Structural layout analysis of document images using Graph Convolutional Neural Networks"
- Conducted part of the thesis during an Erasus+ Traineeship at L3i lab of La Rochelle University.
- Studied during an Erasmus+ Study at Ghent University. Passed Machine Learning, Software Hacking and Parallel Computing exams.

University of Florence Florence, Italy

Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering

2014 - 2017

• Thesis: "Exploiting Convolutional Neural Networks for the detection of walls in floorplan images"

Grants and Certifications

Jun 2023 MLOps Certification, Machine Learning Engineering for Production by DeepLearning.Al Coursera Feb 2023 IAPR Research Scholarship, awarded by the International Association of Pattern Recognition IAPR Feb 2023 IRCDL Student Grant, funded by Associazione Italiana per l'Intelligenza Artificiale AllA Sep 2021 Italian Bar Exam in Information Engineer, with full marks (60/60) UniFi

Selected Publications

Complete list of publications in **Google Scholar** profile.

Doc2Graph: a Task Agnostic Document Understanding Framework based on Graph Neural Networks Andrea Gemelli, Sanket Biswas, Enrico Civitelli, Josep Llados, Simone Marinai TiE @ ECCV22, October 23-27, 2022, Tel Aviv, Israel

Graph Neural Networks and Representation Embedding for Table Extraction in PDF Documents Andrea Gemelli, Emanuele Vivoli, Simone Marinai

ICPR22, August 21-25, 2022, Montréal, Québec

Automatic generation of scientific papers for data augmentation in document layout analysis Lorenzo Pisaneschi, Andrea Gemelli, Simone Marinai

Pattern Recognition Letters 167 (2022) pp. 38-44. 2022

Languages₋